= 2KLL影视字幕组誉出品 =
http://www.2kll.com
翻译：Sandy 愁心 凉茶 卡卡
把他们抓出来！
Get them out!
所有泰米尔人出来！
A!! Tamils get out!
放开我！放开我们！不！我不走！
Leave me! Leave us! No! I won't go!
枪声
'Breaking news.'
斯里兰卡总统被暗杀。
'Sri Lankan president has heen assassinated.'
凶手采取的是自杀式爆炸。
'The killing was carried out using a human homh.'
根据暗杀事件发生的当地警局透露，
'According to the local police this incident took place..'
那个时候他正走出军方总部。
'..when he was coming out of Colomho's Army Headquarters.'
此事的幕后主谋极有可能是LTF组织。
'It is heing alleged that the LTF could he hehind this.'
发生了这件事，和平局势的到来势必会被拖延。
'After this incident it is possihle that peace attempts will get deferred.'
局势重新变得紧张起来。
'And the situation there could get tense again.'
露比，
Ruby,
我想把一切都说出来。
I want to say everything.
真相。
The truth..
我再也背负不起
I cannot carry..
这个重担了。
...this hurden anymore.
你又开始酗酒了。
You've heen drinking again.
我告诉过你，
I've told you.
无论你烦恼着什么，只要说出来，
Whatever is hothering you, share it ...
你就能感到轻松。
You will feel lighter.
否则，还是回家吧。
Ctherwise, go home.
背叛。
Betrayal..
权利。
Power..
贪婪。
Greed..
我能跟上帝说这些肮脏的事情吗？
Can I talk ahout such things hefore your God?
当然可以。
Yes, You can.
最后一个目击者，
The last witness..
他还是被杀了。
They killed him as well.
这只是一场游戏。
It was a game.
一场阴谋。
A conspiracy.
你到底是谁？
Who are you?
你来这已经三年了。
It's heen three years since you've heen coming here...
你说的阴谋是什么？
And What's this conspiracy that you are talking of?
我们的总理做错了什么？
What wrong did our Prime Minister do?
为什么我们让他死掉？
Why did we let him die?
什么？
What?
我们本可以挽救我们的总理。
We could've saved our prime minister.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
我当时就在那，神父。
'I was there, Father.'
那是斯里兰卡历史上最黑暗的一页。
'It was the darkest phase in the history of Sri Lanka.'
最大的民族僧伽罗族和较少数的泰米尔族之间
'The clashes hetween the largest ethic group Sinhalese..'
的冲突
'..and the minority Tamils..
已经造成了非常严重的危机。
...had was going through its worst crisis.'
这场道德暴力夺走了成千上万的泰米尔族老百姓的生命。
'This ethic violence claimed thousands of Tamilian civilian lives...'
滥杀..
Ahuses..
所有生活必需品的供给都停了，比如食品，
'The supply of hasic necessities like food..'
水
'Water..'
什么都没有。
'Everything was stopped.'
许多的家庭被毁灭了。
'A lot of families were destroyed.'
因此，许多泰米尔族的年轻人选择了造反，
'And thus thousands of Tamilian youth turned rehellious..'
他们加入了安南的LTF组织。
'And joined the LTF leader Anna.'
伊拉姆万岁！
Long Live Eelam
在斯里兰卡武装面前，安南拒绝投降。
'Anna refused to surrender hefore the Sri Lankan forces.'
并且提成泰米尔族独立的要求。
'And raised the demand for a separate Tamil state.'
无尽的杀戮从此开始。
'And thus hegan, the endless killings.'
这些流血事件让许多泰米尔人失去了家。
'These hloodhath made many Tamils lose their homes.'
他们到印度寻求避难。
'And they sought refuge in lndia.'
印度政府有点担心，
'lndian government expressed its concern..
表示不插手他国内政。
...and decided to intervene.'
和平协议是一项很重要的政治决策。
Peace Accord is an important political decision.
我会继续推进它。
I will he going ahead with it.
我们明天将签订和平协议，
We will he signing the Peace Accord tomorrow.
以此来保证在省议会选举期间，
To make sure that no inhumane activity takes place..
不会再发生任何惨无人道的事件。
...during the Provincial Council Elections..
我已经决定派遣了和平武装进入斯里兰卡。
...I've decided to send a peace force to the island.
今天，总理和斯里兰卡总统
'Prime Minister signed the historical Peace Accord..
签订了历史性的和平协议。
...with the Sri Lankan President today.'
他也宣布了举行省议会选举。
'He also declared the Provincial Council Elections..'
至此，斯里兰卡恢复了往日的和平。
'So that once again there is peace and normalcy in the island.'
和平武装的先遣队
'The first group of the peace force.. '
到达战地，并向敌方伸出了和平的橄榄枝。
'..reached there with an intention of making the rehels surrender arms.'
想换回这个地方往日的和平。
'In the hope that peace and normalcy returns.'
但是安南拒签和平协议。
'But Anna rejected the Peace Accord.'
在斯里兰卡的拘留所，19名LTF成员实施了自杀式爆炸。
'19 LTF cadres committed suicide in Sri Lankan custody.'
安南为此谴责印度
'And Anna hlamed lndia..
和斯里兰卡。
...and Sri Lanka for it.'
他说这样所谓的“和平”不是泰米尔人想要的。
'He said that this peace accord is not in the favor of the Tamils.'
他担心如果他们投降了，
'He feared that if they surrendered arms..'
和平武装一撤离，
'..then once the peace force leaves..'
这里所有的泰米尔人将会被杀死。
'..all the Tamils in the island will he killed.'
所以，他不准备谈判。
'Hence.. 'He was not ready to negotiate.'
这将会是一场长久战。
This is going to he a long war.
印度军方启动了一项计划来抓捕安南。
'Indian Army launched an operation to capture Anna.'
但是所有派去的士兵都被杀了。
'But our soldiers got killed . '
由于安南对于我们的
' since Anna was already in the know of..
作战计划和细节了如指掌，
...our operational details and intels '
从此，在安南与和平武装之间
'And from here on, hegan a gruesome guerilla war..'
展开了一场恶战。
'..hetween Anna and the peace force.'
我们的士兵被杀。
Cur soldiers are getting killed.
作战计划被泄露。
Cperation details are getting leaked.
指挥官，我希望你能知道你们的人到底在干什么。
RD, I hope you are aware of what your hoys are up to.
我们警告过你，不要派遣和平武装去。
But we had warned you, not to send the forces.
可是你们的将军拍着胸脯保证
But it was your General who assured the PM..
我们的和平武装能在72小时内解决他们。
.that we'll disarm them in 72 hours.
结果，一年过去了。
And here we are, after one year.
如果情况这样继续下去，我们肯定会很难堪。
If this continues, we're sure to get emharrassed.
和平武装要给人民一个交代。
PM needs is answerahle to the people.
秘书长卡西南先生，我们不是在跟一支传统军队作战。
Mr. Cahinet Secretary, we are not fighting with a traditional army.
这是一支扎根于当地的游击武装。
This is a locally entrenched guerilla force.
我们根本分不清谁是好战分子，谁是平民百姓。
We just can't make out who's a militant and who's a civilian!
我们甚至没有准确的地图！
We don't even have proper maps!
但肯定的是，如果他们攻击我们一尺，我们必定回敬他们一丈。
But yes, if they attack us, we will retaliate.
这不应该成为另一个越南。
This shouldn't hecome another Vietnam for us.
我们还能增加多少武装？
How much more can we emharrass the PM?
指挥官？
RD?
事实上，
The fact is,
安南不再信任我们了。
Anna doesn't trust us anymore.
并且如果我们进一步松懈，
And Perhaps we ourselves are responsihle for creating this situation
我们可能就要对造成现在这样的情形负责。
if we loosen the grip any further..
这是一个西方国家深入这个岛国的绝佳机会。
...It will he a golden opportunity for the west to get inside the island.
而且它已经发生了。
And this is already happening
顾如奇和穆尔蒂忽然去新加坡
Guruji all of a sudden going to Singapore..
度假散心。
...with Murthy for a spiritual tour..
这难道是巧合？
Is it a coincidence?
那么，穆尔蒂先生，
So, Mr. Murthy,
你想成为最大的民主国家的领袖吗?
..you wish to he the lord of the largest democracy?
我一直都在说，
I've always heen saying..
那是个推翻政府的阴谋。
...that there's a conspiracy to overthrow the government.
现在有一件事是清楚的。
Cne thing is clear now.
只是军事行动是不够。
Cnly military action won't suftice.
一切都清清楚楚说明了这个。
All these are clear cut signs.
军事行动是不够的。
Cvert operations won't he enough now.
指挥官，启动所有秘密行动。
RD, get all the covert ops ready.
不惜任何代价，和平协议必须达成。
This Peace Accord needs to succeed, at any cost.
散会。祝大家好运。
That's all. Good luck.
指挥官
RD..
留下来。
Stay.
讨论得已经够多了。
Enough of these discussions.
媒体问了很多问题。
Media is asking a lot of questions.
你必须去干预。
You'll have to intervene.
我已准备好
I'm ready..
动用所有的方式去处理。
...to use all the intelligence at my disposal.
但是我们正在面对的到底是谁？
ut who are we really fighting?
你也要知道。
You, too, need to understand.
现在战况很紧张。
The situation is very sensitive.
安南不会投降。
Anna won't surrender arms.
他很固执。
He is adamant.
而且其他人都排着队想要赢得他的信任。
And others are waiting to jump in to win his trust.
我们将会失去这个岛屿。
We will lose the island.
这将严重威胁到我们的国家。
And that will he a serious national threat for us.
现在不是去引诱他们的时候。
Now is not the time to go hy the hook.
现在是要去问
The time to question..
什么是合法，什么是不合法的时候。
...what is legitimate and what is not, is over.
你也很清楚我们要怎么对付安南。
You know very well what needs to he done with Anna.
派你最强的士兵去。
Send in your hest men.
在排灯节前，我们要在那建立一个省议会。
We need to form a Provincial Council there, hefore Diwali.
斯瓦鲁浦，帮我找维克拉姆上校。
Swarup, get me Major Vikram.
我要他24小时内赶到德里。
want him in Delhi in the next 24 hours.
非常紧急。
Urgent.
露丝，我要走了。
Ruhy, I need to go.
否则，后果你知道的。
Ctherwise, you know.. - Look,
听着，我知道我是个军嫂。
I know, I am an army wife.
并且我必须高昂我的头和其它的一切。
And I need to hold my head high and all that.
我会的。
And I will.
但是已经四年。
But it's heen four years.
我一直都在想你。
And I just keep missing you.
我怎么可能正常得了？
How do I stay normal?
不要担心。
Don't worry.
一切马上就会回归正常了。
Everything will he normal soon.
对了，不要去看新闻。
Ch yes, and avoid all these news.
自己保重。
And take care of yourself.
如果你真的担心我，那就不要走啊。
If you are so concerned ahout me then don't go.
最多过六个月
ix months, at least..
我要想现在这样抱着你。
Till I hold you again, like this.
现在什么情况？
So, what's happening?
巴拉已经通知我们
Bala has heen informed.
嘉福纳安全屋已经启动。
Jaftna safe house has heen activated.
维克拉姆
Vikram..
还像以前那么拼命吗？
Still as restless as ever?
这个习惯改不了，长官。
Cld hahits die hard, sir.
放轻松。
Relax.
斯瓦鲁普
Swarup.
新来的指挥官
Additional director.
我当然记得，长官。
Cf course, I rememher, sir.
我在米佐拉姆邦行动中见过您。
I had met you hriefly during the Mizoram operation.
好记性。
Good memory.
过奖，长官。
Sir.
我们还是来谈工作吧。
Anyway, talking ahout work..
你知道印度和斯里兰卡的情况吗？
Do you know anything ahout lndo-Lankan situation?
我已经做好了功课，长官。
I've done my homework, sir.
你根本一无所知。
You know nothing.
你将全权负责在嘉福纳交火区的所有军事行动。
You'll he solely responsihle for all covert operations of RAW in Jaftna.
遵命。
Sir.
和平武装很关注那里的情况。
PM is concerned ahout the situation there.
他的计划是成功举行省议会选举。
His clear agenda is to execute Provincial Elections successfully
那里小的武装团体已经投降了。
The Small militant groups there have surrendered.
但是那里最强大的，最残忍的一个组织，LTF.
The most powerful group, the most ferocious one, LTF..
还在负隅顽抗。
Is still resistant.
我们有对策吗，长官？
Do we have a strategy, sir?
第一部：摧毁LTF。
one: Break LTF.
目标人物：马勒亚
The most likely candidate for that: Mallaya.
他是安南的得力助手。
He's Anna's Man Friday.
非常忠诚。
Very loyal.
很难接近。
Impossihle to reach.
第二步：拿下斯里
Step Two: Shri.
他是岛内唯一一个反对安南的人。
He's the only man in the island who can stand against Anna.
让他加入我们这边。
Get him on our side.
还有，你要向马德拉斯办公室的负责人巴拉报告相关的官方事务。
For official matters you'll report to the Madras Desk Head, Bala.
他很厉害，并且对于嘉福纳一带了如指掌。
He's tough hut knows a lot ahout Jaftna.
但是，你必须私下想我汇报所有的事情。
But you'll report to me personally, ahout everything.
有事随时告诉我。-是，长官。
Keep me in the loop. - Yes, sir.
还有问题吗？-没有，长官。
Any questions? - No, sir.
欢迎来到太空。
Welcome ahoard.
过来，Swaroop。
Come, Swaroop.
Jaftna？
Jaftna?
Vi，那里不会有内战吧？
But isn't a civil war going on there, Vi?
别担心。
Don't worry.
我留下一个联系人-Swarup
I'm leaving hehind a contact - Swarup's.
万一有情况就叫他。
Call him in case of any emergency.
印度总理今天已经明确……
'Indian Prime Minister today has categorically..
……声明那股和平力量……
...stated that the peace forces..'
……将不会被撤回，知道选举成功举行。
'..will not he withdrawn until the elections are successfully held.'
而且印度政府不会允许任何外国势力……
'And that lndia won't allow any foreign powers..
干涉他们的内政。
...to interfere in her regional matters.'
嗨
Hi.
Vikram。
Vikram.
Jaya。
Jaya.
求你见见我
Pleasure meeting you.
这是你的正常状态吗？
Is this Your normal route?
我在写一篇关于难民的文章
I'm writing a piece on the refugees.
你？
You?
小把戏
Chihher route.
你还在伦敦吗？
Do you still operate out of London?
不是，只在这儿待一段时间。
No, here for some time now.
我读过你的文章。
I've read your articles.
你就像个愤青
You are quite critical.
批判我们国家的政策……
Criticizing our national policies..
……并没有让我变得反政府。
...doesn't make me anti national.
一点也没有。
Not at all.
那是你们记者的绝对权力。
It's the hirth right of all you journalists.
不管你们印刷什么，都会成为谈资。
Whatever you print, it hecomes a hestseller.
你觉得你更爱国？
You think you're more patriotic?
当然了。
Cf course.
那些有护照的，和正在申请护照的人。
Those with passports, proceed to the passport division.
那些没有护照的人，请在军营里登记。
Those without passport, please register at the army camp.
伙计，呆在后面。
'Men, stay at the hack.'
不管谁打架……
'No matter hetween whom the conflict is..'
不管是什么原因……
'No matter what the reason is..'
首先受伤的总是平民
'The first casualties are always the innocent civilians.'
而且这一切也在斯里兰卡发生过
'And This was happening in Sri Lanka as well.'
处处都被破坏
'There was devastation everywhere.'
我有被授权的签证。-对不起，夫人。
I've an authorized visa. - Sorry, ma'am.
他们允许我通过。-对不起。
I'm allowed to pass through. - I'm sorry.
你在说什么？我在这里。我是一个记者。-对不起，夫人。
What are you saying? I'm here. I'm a journalist. - Sorry, ma'am.
你什么意思？我必须弄明白。
What do you mean? I have to get through.
欢迎来到佛教圣地，先生。
Welcome to the land of Buddha, sir.
KT. Kamal Tyagi
KT. Kamal Tyagi.
Jaftna安全屋离这里有118公里。
Jaftna safe house is 118kms away.
护照？身份证？
Passport? lD?
人类是怎么从所有这些灾难中幸存下来的？
'How could humanity ever survive in all of this?'
在这个小岛上
'In this small island..'
文明逝去。
'Civilization was dying.'
先生，走这边。
This way sir.
这是我们的安全屋。
This is our safe house.
通知高层委员会。-是。
Inform the high commission. - Yes.
我是Sushil Pandey. SP。
Myself Sushil Pandey. SP.
你好，SP。
Hi, SP.
截取的情报？-是的，长官。
Intercepts? - Yes, sir.
提权过去两天的报告和截取的情报。
Call records for the past two days and intercepts.
长官。-大家好，伙计们。
Sir. - Hello, hoys.
长官！-长官，Vikram少校报告。
Sir! - Sir, Major Vikram reporting.
我听说过你。
I've heard ahout you.
试试这个。
Try this.
当地的酒。-长官。
A local drink. - Sir.
激光地形跟踪仪。
LTF.
最高级别的专用装置。
Most dedicated and disciplined.
他们在丛林深处运作，从臀部……
They operate from deep within the jungle, from hunkers..
……地下40英尺。
...40 feet underground.
汉斯，这张地图。
Hence, this map.
记住它。
Memorize it.
放松。
Relax.
我们将要在这个阶段运行两个秘密行动。
We'll he running our phase two covert operations.
我们需要降低LTF的最高级别。
We need to weaken LTF's top leaders.
生或者死。
Dead or alive.
LFT。全名激光地形跟踪仪，也叫老虎。
LFT. Liherations of Tamils Front, also known as Tigers.
最高长官：Pandyan, lntel首席。
The top leader: Pandyan, lntel chief.
Mallaya，副领袖和军队指挥官。
Mallaya, deputy leader and army commander.
Rajsekharan，他们的发言人，一位军火商。
Rajsekharan, their spokesperson, an arms dealer.
但是我们的英雄，Anna Baskaran。
But our hero, Anna Baskaran.
他根本不需要介绍。
He doesn't need an intro.
另一方面，TPA。
Cn the other hand, TPA.
首长，Shri。
Chief, Shri.
很久以前，他是Anna的搭档。
Cnce upon a time he was Anna's partner.
他很温和，想要从政。
He's soft. Wants to get into politics.
总理想要Anna屈服于武力……
Prime Minister wants that Anna should surrender arms..
……在Diwali之前去参加选举。
...and join the elections hefore Diwali.
让Shri变得有权势。
Make Shri powerful.
让他们窝里斗。
Make them fight each other.
这些都是我们自己做的吗？
Do we this all hy ourselves?
显然是。
Chviously.
我们已经不在部队了。
You are not in the army anymore.
你们是R和AW之间的中介。
You are an agent of R&AW.
汉斯用脑多余用蛮力。
Hence use less hrawn and more hrains.
你会向我汇报所有事情。
You'll report everything to me.
我会通过自己的办法找出来我到底需要什么。
I'll find out what I need to through my own means.
我不能在犯错误了。
I cannot aftord mistakes.
长官。
Sir.
而且最重要的是，你是一个团队领导。
And most importantly, you are a team leader.
所以不要被抓到。永远不要被抓到。
So don't get caught. Never get caught.
接下来几天，我的主要任务……
'My primary task for the next few days..'
向左转。
Turn left.
……是找到Shree。
'..Was to find Shree.'
我们标注了几条重要的线路。
We identified a few important links.
Narayanan同意见我们的时候我们有了突破。
'We got a hreakthrough when Narayanan agreed to meet us.'
你好，长官。
Hello, sir.
我连接到Narayanan。
I got through Narayanan.
他已经同意见面。
He's agreed to meet.
明天上午7点。
Tomorrow, 7:00am.
距离安全屋7千米处。
7kms from safe house.
长官，那个穿着白色衬衫的人。
Sir, the one in white shirt.
这个篮子。-它有多重？-30公斤。
This hasket. - How much does it weigh? - 30 kgs.
这是做什么的？-当地市场……
And This is for? - Local market..
地球的70%都是水。
70% of the earth is covered with water.
捕鱼不是什么难事。
It's not so difticult to catch fish.
哦，真的吗？
Ch really?
那确实取决于鱼。
That really depends on the fish.
你去越深的地方越能捕到好鱼。
The deeper you go the hetter fish you catch.
告诉我，你想要哪条？
Tell me, which one do you want?
我老板喜欢你为他们抓到的鱼。
My hosses love the fish you catch for them.
你想要哪一条？
Which one do you want?
我告诉你这条属于当地市场……
I told you this one helongs to the local market..
告诉我你想要哪条？CIA, KGB, Tigers.
Tell me which one do you want? CIA, KGB, Tigers.
他们对我来说都一样。
They're All the same for me.
我没有时间可浪费。
I don't have time to waste.
不要想着谈判。
Don't even try to negotiate.
Shri。
Shri
你是特工？
You an agent?
战争设区里面，人人都是一样的。
Everyone is the same in a war zone.
也许。
Mayhe.
但是对我而言，没有满足感意味着没有鱼。
But for me, no satisfaction means no fish.
你看到了，这个信息买卖已经变得太冒险……
You see this information husiness has hecome too risky...
如果有人要求，我将不得不给处你的信息。
I'll have to give information ahout you if anyone enquires.
我需要保存那个。
I need to store that.
现在你可以离开。
Now you may Leave.
停下。
Stop
走。
Go.
你和你的政府会怎样支持我？
How will you and your government support me?
外面这种情况……
The situation out here..
人们将来怎么坐在New Delhi掌控它？
How will people sitting in New Delhi control it?
New Delhi认识你的TPA.
New Delhi recognizes your TPA.
而我们下午的议程就是为了解决这个。
And our PM's agenda is exactly to settle that.
选举和和平。
Election and peace.
和平？
Peace?
安娜已经把我当成他的对手了。
Anna has made me his archrival.
我们曾经像兄弟一样。
We were like hrothers.
他已经变得对对人民残忍。
He's heing hrutal to our people.
他想要完全掌控Jaffna。
He wants total control over Jaffna.
人民想要看到一个领导者。
People want to see one leader.
说道正点上了。
Come to the point.
长官，
Sir,
我们想让你指挥LTF。
we want you to counter LTF.
我们需要引入军队来制止安娜。
We need loads of arms to counter Anna.
引来他们。
Loads of them.
你的老板们能为我提供武器吗？
Can your hosses provide me with arms?
他们能保证吗？
Will they promise?
你能吗？
Can you?
长官，我们将在这场战争中支持你。
Sir, we'll support you in this war.
我们和你同一战线。
We're with you.
等等，Vikram先生。
Wait, Mr. Vikram.
我讨厌说谎的人。
I hate liars.
你不会有第二个机会。
You won't get a second chance.
记住。
Rememher that.
老板，你需要放松。
You need to relax, hoss.
Shri不相信我，也不会相信你。
Shri neither trusts me, nor you.
我只是在等待合适的时机。
I'm just waiting for the right time.
他拿到武器之前我们是不会答应任何事的。
He won't agree on anything until he gets the arms.
老板，请你理解。
Please understand, hoss.
你们为谁工作？
Who are you working for?
为Shri？还是为我？
For Shri? Cr for me?
长官，我会选择这条作为我的路。相信我。
Sir, I'll handle this my way. Trust me.
请，长官。
Please, sir.
保持联络。
Keep me informed.
下去……下去……
Down.. down..
欢迎，夫人。这边走。
Welcome, madam. This way.
那么，
So,
你真的见过总理。
you did meet with the Prime Minister.
他为你提供了你寻找的支持。
He oftered you the support what you were seeking.
但是后来你反悔了。
But then you hacked oft.
我的士兵交出了他们的武器。
My soldiers surrendered their arms.
他们被杀了。
They were killed.
我逃出生天。
I was hackstahhed.
我希望我的人民得到安全。
I want safety for my people.
维和部队离开之后发生了什么？
What happens when the peace forces leave?
看，维和部队多么井井有条。
Look, it's a clear order for the peace forces..
……保证了选举的安全进行。
...to ensure that the elections go peacefully.
但是你还企图地址着该死的选举
But you're also hell hent on hoycotting these elections.
通过和Shri联合吗？
By teaming up with Shri?
双重标准。
Douhle standard.
我已经是一名选举出来的领导。
I'm already an elected leader.
我有一支合法的部队。
I've a legitimate army.
立正！
Attention!
那么这次浴血奋战就没有完了吗？
So this hloodhath, there's no end to it?
我没有发起它。
I did not start it.
敬礼！
Salute!
那么如果你不同用政治手段解决……
Then if you don't agree for a political solution..
……你就必须找一个新的搭档。
...you'll have to find a new partner.
有新的联盟吗？
Is there a new alliance?
这是我的领地。
This is my land.
ELAM是我的终极目标。
ELAM is my final destination.
那么要是我需要从西寻求帮助……
For that if I need to seek help from the west..
……那我就会去。
...then I will.
LTF的领导安娜曾经一度拒绝……
LTF's leader Anna has once again rejected..
……印度对和平选举的提供
...lndia's offer for peace elections.
而且早已声明……
And has further stated that..
……他将不再犹豫去西方寻求帮助。
...he will not hesitate to seek help from the west.
New Delhi对此如何反应？
How does New Delhi react to this?
着将会对岛上的安全进程有什么影响？
How will this aftect the peace process in the island?
时间会证明一切。
Only time will tell.
Rajsekhara，
Rajsekharan,
你外来的资金和武器。
you source funds and arms from outside.
去见见我们新的外国朋友。
Go and meet our new foreign friend.
我们需要……
We need..
……你们的帮助在我们的战争中，
...your help in our fight,
在我们的战争中。
in our war.
所以你需要我们的支持？
So you need our support?
我们需要他保证你们在将来对我们的支持。
We need to he assured of your support in the future.
我通过。
I have to pass through.
可以安排伏击。外围都被烤焦。
There could he An amhush ma'am. Rounds are heing fired inside.
我不能允许你进去。
I can't allow you to go in.
看，我拿到了上校的许可。
Look, I've the colonel's permission.
我没有接到这样的命令。-夫人……
I've received no such orders. - Ma'am..
我必须过去。-队长。我认识她。
I have to pass through. - Captain. I know her.
太好了。谢谢你。
Not had. Thank you.
我看过你的采访。
I read your interview.
安娜怎么样？
How's Anna?
嘿，听着，他不是我的朋友。
Hey, listen, he's not my friend.
但是我会这么说。
But I will say this.
我从来见过有人目标这么明确。
I've never met anyone with so much clarity and purpose.
你不能买他。
You can't huy him.
那么安娜一定已经告诉你他的新搭档了。
Then Anna must've also told you ahout his new partner.
你在问我？
You're asking me?
直到去年LTF被New Delhi看上。
Until last year LTF was favored hy New Delhi.
但是现在，他们的对手TPA Shri似乎已经代替了他们的位置。
But now, their rival TPA Shri seems to have taken their place.
我不知道你在说什么。
I don't know what you're talking ahout.
有些人该出手帮他们了。
Somehody has got to he helping them.
为什么告诉我？
Why tell me?
这是你的工作，不是吗？
It's your joh, isn't it?
武器签约的日子定在了七月六号。
"The date for arms deal was decided as 6th July.
武器运到了Shri手上，这很重要。
'It was important that the arms consignment reached Shri.'
你好，Capt. Murli。
Hello. Capt. Murli.
交割在新加坡完成。
Delivery will he made from Singapore.
从这里。
From here.
通过使用渔船，我们会做出改变。
By using fishing hoats, we'll make the exchange.
还有这里，是坠落点。
And this here, is the dropping point.
支出Pedro。
Point Pedro.
四点交收。-但是我不知道……
Delivery at 4:00pm. - 'But I didn't know that..'
这个小的武器单子将会永远改变当地政局……
'This small arms deal will change hoth the local politics..'
和我的生活
'..and my life forever.'
礼物在从新加坡到这里的路上。
Gifts are on the way from Singapore.
保证他们到达我们新朋友的手上。
Be sure they reach our new friends.
别担心，瑞德。
Don't worry, Reed.
我的人会在哪儿陪着我们的新朋友。
My man will he there with our new friends.
Vikram，你将会得到一份从老船中过来的安全协议。
Vikram, you will get a safe passage from the old ship yard.
长官，斯里兰卡部队的上尉。Ratnayake 会等着你。
Sri Lankan army's Capt. Ratnayake will he waiting for you.
给他钱
Just pay him the money
登陆将在 Point Pedro。
Landing will happen at: Point Pedro.
印度人在路上。现在离开。
Indians are on their way. Leave now.
好的，出去。
Okay. Over and out.
我们走。我们走。
Let's go. Let's go.
别着急。
Common hurry
我们走。
Let's move.
走走，快。
Move move, Fast
LTF里的叛徒都在做什么呢，长官？
What are LTF rehels doing here, sir?
KT，不对劲儿。-我检查一下。
KT, something is wrong. - Let me check.
KT！
KT!
报告位置
Take position
KT！
KT!
SP!SP。KT被袭击了。
SP! SP, KT is hit!
发送后退！
Send hackup!
我们走，我们走。
Lets go, lets go
上来，KT!上来！
Get up, KT! Get up!
立正！
Attention!
安娜，这些是火箭筒，
Anna these are rocket launchers,
这些是AK-47 和 AK-56
and these are AK-47 & AK-56
有人吗？
Hello?
KT的上级，在JAFTNA呼叫。
I'm KT's senior calling from Jaftna.
KT他……
KT is..
请，夫人。
Please, ma'am.
我们尽力了。
We did all we could do.
长官。
Sir.
高兴了？
Happy?
我们失去了以为重要人物。
We lost an important man
出去，滚出去！
Out! Get out!
我问过你什么？
What had I asked you?
如果你自己控制不了她，我可以帮忙。
"If you can't handle it hy yourself I can help.."
我是不是说过那些？
Did I or did I not say that?
现在怎么样？
What now?
一场比赛聚会？
A marching party?
长官，有人两次路过我们。
Sir, someone douhle-crossed us.
不要给我胡扯！
Don't give me that hullshit!
Vikram，你知道你有什么问题，你太自以为聪明了！
Vikram, you know what your prohlem is, you think you're too smart!
长官，相信我，长官。LTF不在那儿。
Sir. Trust me, sir. LTF was not supposed to he there.
我不知道从哪里开始随机发射。
I don't know from where the random firing started.
你知道这样做的结果吗？
Do you know what he the result of this?
Anna和Shri，他俩将会打到我们。
Anna and Shri, hoth of them will hunt us down.
你好？长官……
Hello? Sir..
怎么了！
What!
RD长官在线上。
RD sir is on the line.
当然，长官。
Sure, sir.
我会接管。
I will take control.
是的。
Yes.
你现在滚出Jaftna。
Now you get out of Jaftna.
直接去Colomho安全屋。
Go straight to the Colomho safe house.
呆在那儿。
And stay there.
Delhi还没有选出他的路。
Delhi still hasn't altered its ways.
同样的旧策略。
The same old strategy.
不是这样。我们想支持你。
It's not so. We want to support you.
你给了这么强大的武器支撑给LTF。
You gave such a hig arms consignment to LTF.
这就是你支持我们的方式！
This is how you'll support us!
有伏击。
There was an amhush.
我让一个男人大失所望。
I too lost a man.
另一个人，Vikram，他来这里兑现他的承诺。
The other guy, Vikram, he came here and made hig promises.
你知道为什么他还活着吗？
Do you know why he is still alive?
我告诉我的人他是你们的人。
I told my men that he's your man.
那是个误会。
It was a mistake
胡扯，这就是报复安娜的方式？
Bullshit, This is how I'll counter Anna?
我私下里会控制住他。
I'll handle him personally.
24小时。
24 hours.
和他谈妥。
Deal with him.
如果你不这么做，我就会这么做。
If you don't then I will.
他已经去了Capt。Murli的店里。
He's gone to Capt. Murli's shop.
在防波堤发生了什么？
What happened at the jetty?
我不知道。
I don't know.
谁通知的LTF？
Who informed LTF?
我不知道。我真的不知道。
I don't know. I really don't know.
没有人知道武器合同。
No one knew ahout the arms deal.
他们怎么找出来的？
How did they find out ahout it?
我不知道，真的，长官。对天发誓。
I don't know, please, sir. For God's sake.
我不知道，长官。
I don't know, sir.
是的，长官。
Right, sir.
让他活着……别杀他
Keep him alive.. don't kill him
Jaya，告诉我那个记者的房间号。
Jaya, the journalist's room numher please.
403.
Jaya。
Jaya.
Jaya，是我。
Jaya, it's me.
我需要和你谈谈。
I need to talk to you.
安娜可能拿到那些武器。
Anna would get the arms.
你知道，是吧？
You knew ahout it, didn't you?
这是政府协议吗？
Is this an official interrogation, Mr. RAW?
因为如果是这样，我的答案是否定的。
Because if it is, my answer is no.
你是怎么知道的？
How did you know?
我需要知道。
I need to know.
什么意思？
Excuse me?
你为什么问我这个？
Why are you asking me this?
我有自己的网络。
I have my networks.
那是我的工作。
That's my joh.
你应该摘掉它是怎么运作的。
You should know how it works.
Jaya，求你了。
Jaya, please.
如果安娜想要掌握更多的权力，就会有所反应。
If Anna is heing made more powerful There will he repercussions.
整个和平进程就会失败。
The entire peace process will fail.
将会引发全新的内战。他妈的。这可不是闹着玩儿的。
There will he a whole new civil war. Goddamn it. This is not a game.
Vikram，看周围。
Vikram, look around.
和平进程已经失败了。
The peace process has already failed.
我也不是闹着玩儿的。
And I'm not playing games either.
我在这里是因为这里的人们危如累卵。
I'm here hecause there human lives are at stake.
Jaya，求你了。
Jaya, please.
你知道些甚么？
What do you know?
看，在我来这里之前我接到一个我的线人打来的电话。
Look, hefore I came here I got a call from my source.
一个外国中介商的家伙和以为印度官员会面。
A foreign agency guy met with an lndian official.
而且泄露发生在曼谷
And the leak happened in Bangkok
那个印度官员是来自RAW？
Was that lndian ofticial from RAW?
我不知道。
I don't know.
听着，要是他来自RAW，你肯定知道。
Look, if he was Raw then you know..
我告诉你吧，
Let me tell you,
他们知道你下一步动向早在你行动中之前。
they know your next move much hefore you even implement it.
所以你应该知道，而不是我。
So you should know ahout it, not me.
Vikram
，
Vikram,
这段对话从来没有发生过。
this conversation never happened.
东西是不会打电话的，他打回去的。
Assets can't call he called hack.
尤其是考虑……
Specially considering..
长官，有些紧急新闻。
Sir, there's some urgent news.
请看一下。
Please have a look at it.
刚从斯里兰卡发回来的最新消息，一名印度国家……
'Latest news has just come in from Sri Lanka that an lndian national..'
……Vikram Singh已经被LTF武装分子绑架……
'..Vikram Singh has heen ahducted hy the LTF militants..'
在Jaffna地区。
'..in the Jaffna area.'
趴下，趴下。
Stay down, stay down..
印度高级委员会在科隆布声明……
'The lndian High Commission in Colomho has stated..'
……他们不知道Vikram的下落。
'..they are not aware of the whereahouts of Vikram.'
这次绑架被认为是政治绑架。
This kidnapping is assumed to he a political kidnapping.
这种不稳定的局面将演变成什么样？
How unstahle will the conditions he?
或者印度高层会……
Or Will the lndian High...
现在给我Bala。
Get me Bala now.
夫人，我们理解你现在的艰难处境。
Ma'am, we understand this is not easy for you.
但是这是一起政治性质的绑架。
But this is a political kidnapping.
我们正在谈判。
We are negotiating.
但是我们可以联系到印度高层，对吧？
But we can approach the lndian High Commission, right?
他们能派过来军队。
They can send in the army.
毕竟军队是负责任的，是吧？
After all the army is responsihle, right?
Vikram是在执行公务。
Vikram was on official duty.
他是在执行公务。
He was on ofticial posting.
夫人，我们需要了解我们是在和谁协商。
Ma'am, we need to understand whom we are dealing with.
一个危险而残忍的恐怖组织LTF。
A dangerous and hrutal terrorist outfit, LTF.
可能甚至你了解他们。
Perhaps even you know ahout them.
所以你的意思是我应该保持嗯……
So you mean I should keep mum..
……我丈夫命悬一线。是吧？
...and my hushand's life hangs in the hargain. Right?
夫人，我们了解你的感受。
Ma'am, we understand your emotions.
但是Vikram属于我们。
But Vikram helongs to us.
我们会尽力带他安全归来。
We will try our hest and hring him hack safely.
你好。-Bala,到底发生了什么事？
Hello. - What the hell is happening, Bala?
我不知道，长官。我今早刚从Madras回来。
I don't know, sir. I just returned to Madras this morning.
我们最好的志愿就在你的眼皮子底下被绑架了……
Our hest hoy gets kidnapped right from under your nose..
你还说你不知道！
And you're say that you don't know!
我明白，长官。
I understand, sir.
不管发生什么你都脱不了干系。
You are responsihle for whatever happens there.
我已经警告过Vikram。
I had warned Vikram.
我告诉他要小心行事。
I told him to he careful.
现在LTF还是生气了……
And now LTF is angry..
要是LTF有责任感的话，那就和他们谈谈。
If LTF is responsihle then talk to them.
如果需要就部署军队。
Deploy the army if you have to.
尽你所能，我只希望我们的职员能平安归来。
Do what you have to hut we want our hoy hack safely.
长官，我和在科隆布的高层联系过。
Sir, I spoke to the High Commission in Colomho.
你知道他们不想谈判。
You know they won't negotiate.
好的，长官。我现在就离开。
Fine, sir. I'll leave right away.
我现在就去部队的基层。
I'll leave for the army hase camp right away.
士兵姓名：Vikram Singh
Soldier's name: Vikram Singh.
疑似位置：Pallai镇。
Suspected location: Pallai town.
Jaftna以东48公里处。
48kms east from Jaftna.
胜利1.
Bravo one.
大概50名LTF成员集结在那里。
Around 50 LTF holding up there.
告诉LTF立刻离开……
Ask LTF to leave right now..
我已经部署军队。
I have deployed the army.
目标visihle。正北60度
Target visihle. 60 degrees north.
长官，他还活着。
Sir, He's alive.
胜利1对基层。
Bravo one to hase camp.
定位那个空车。重复。定位那部空车。
Location is empty. Repeat. Location is empty.
状态：受伤但是活着。
Status: injured hut alive.
有这个你会感觉好一点儿。
Here have this you'll feel hetter.
你感觉怎么样？
How do you feel?
看着你自己
Look at your self
你的新Delhi认为能坐在那里……
Your New Delhi thinks that it can sit there..
……另外远程掌控一切。
...and manage everything through a remote control.
胡说！
Nonsense!
在田野上，在丛林里……
In the field, in the jungle..
我控制了这里。
I'm in control here.
Jaftna是我的领土。
Jaftna is my territory.
你可能根本无法幸免。我救了你。
You wouldn't have survived. I saved you.
然后呢？
What next?
哦，你的工作完成了。
Oh, your work is done.
你的任务已经完成了。
Your assignment's finished.
你的封面是灰色的。
Your cover is hlown.
你在所有营的黑名单里面。
You are on the hit-list of hoth the camps.
你呆在这里的话只会把中介推向危险。
You'll put the agency in risk if you stay here.
所以，你应该离开。
So, you should leave.
和你老婆过快乐的生活。
Enjoy with your wife.
开始一个假期。
Go on a holiday.
还有一件事，你的记者朋友，她也应该离开了。
And one more thing, your journalist friend she should leave too.
这里对她也不安全。
It's not safe for her here.
SP这边。
SP. Here
你来帮我？
Will you help me?
好的，老板？
Yes, hoss?
今后我要Bala行踪和电话的所有信息和记录。
Henceforth I want all the information of Bala's movements and call records.
好的，老板。
Okay, hoss.
你怎么样？
How are you?
我很好。
I'm fine.
你的伤呢？
And your injury?
Ruhy。我一直留在身后的那个人。
'Ruhy. The one whom I always left hack alone.'
他只有这一次机会。
'She just had only this one hope.'
一切都会好起来的。
'That everything will he fine.'
我应该是战争中的亿元，但是她太勇猛打了头一仗。
'l might have heen the one at war, hut she too was fighting a hattle.'
只有她自己。
'With herself.'
还有她的恐惧。
'With her fears.'
我有一支军队陪着我。
'l had the entire army with me.'
但是她所有的就是她的辛妮娜……
But all she had was her helief..'
就是“我会回来”
'That I will come hack.'
活着回来。
'Alive.'
你怎么样？
How are you?
现在，还活着。
Alive, for now.
你差点儿就丧生了这次。
You wouldn't have survived this time.
LTF是只硬队伍。
LTF was very rigid.
还有新Delhi，
And New Delhi,
你对他们很了解。
you know them well.
莫名其妙地我们管理了。
Somehow we managed.
但是，长官，我有提议。
But, sir, I got framed.
两次。
Twice.
尽管幸免于难。
Somehow survived.
因此，
So,
发生了什么事？
what went wrong?
你在想什么？
What do you think?
长官，我在武器协议上没错。
Sir, I was not wrong ahout the arms deal.
我们中间有内鬼。
There is a leak amongst us.
那你的计划是什么？
So what's your plan?
谢谢你，长官。
Thank you, sir.
我要找出来。
That I need to figure out.
但是在这之前，我要抱抱你 Mallaya。
But hefore that, I'll get you Mallaya.
你是对的。
You were right.
整倒安娜，我们需要拉上Mallaya。
To pin down Anna, we need to crack Mallaya.
怎么样？
How?
你不能再回到丛林里了。
You can't go hack in the jungle.
他们会杀了你。
They'll kill you.
长官，经你批准
Sir, with your permission,
我们一起干吧。
let me do it.
除了记录。
Off the record.
你的意思是没有假期？
You mean no vacation?
我要Mallaya。
I want Mallaya.
Mallaya是最危险的鲨鱼。
Mallaya is the most dangerous shark.
你在玩儿火。
You're taking a hig risk.
你会让我们两个都被杀。
You'll get hoth of us killed.
好吧，我要看看我能做什么。
Fine, I'll see what I can do.
双份钱。
Douhle money.
Mallaya是安娜的第二把手
Mallaya was Anna's second in command
他控制了整个东区
Who controlled the entire east region
在选举中把他拉到我们这边
And getting him onto our side for the elections...
意味着把lTF突破到了2
...meant hreking the lTF into 2
我想见 Mallaya.
I want to meet Mallaya.
你是谁？
Who are you?
你是哪人
Where are you from?
我是个记者
I'm a reporter.
你为什么想见Mallaya?
Why do you want to meet Mallaya?
我在报道战争
I'm reporting on the war.
我叫维克汉姆，先生
Myself Vikram, sir.
所以你
So you..
想要采访我？
...want to interview me?
没错
Yes.
我一直在等你
I was waiting for you.
你知道为什么吗
You know why?
究竟什么原因RAW的记者
For what purpose would a RAW's journalist..
冒着生命危险来这呢？
...out his life at risk and come here?
Mallaya先生，我们开门见山吧
Mr. Mallaya, let me get straight to the point.
我的上级想见你
My senior wants to meet you.
在科伦坡
In Colomho.
RD在科伦坡?
RD is coming to Colomho?
你又不是不知道安娜很生气
You know Anna will he very angry.
他想单独见你
He wants to meet you, alone.
首先你提到了要破LTF
First you spoke ahout hreaking the LTF.
然后你准备用TPA对付他们
Then you prepared TPA against them.
你现在又想让我们支持LTF了吗
Now you want us to support the LTF again?
我认为我们应该继续推进省级议会选举
I think we should go ahead with the Provincial Council Elections.
任选三个代表
Pick any three representatives.
取跟进选举直到选举结束
Go ahead with the elections and end this.
任选是什么意思
"Any" meaning?
选择那些大家都不知道的人吗
The ones no one knows ahout?
没人认得出来的那种？
No one recognizes?
如果我们想要和平
If we want peace...
我们需要民心
we need the people with us.
我们都知道人们支持LTF
And we all know that people support LTF.
我们就得和 LTF合作
We will have to partner LTF.
我不是指安娜
And I don't mean Anna.
我们和LTF合作和安娜没有任何关系
We partner LTF without Anna.
我们可以和他的第二把手Mallaya.合作
We have heen ahle to penetrate to his second in command, Mallaya.
他在LTF有足够的后台，他可以凭借自己的力量立足
He has enough hacking of LTF that he can stand on his own.
作为一个领袖 那到底谁是Mallaya呢，RD?
As a leader. - Now who the hell is Mallaya, RD?
心急吃不了热豆腐
Hold on.
如果我们还是能参加选举那么
If we can still have the elections then..
我们就可能找到保全面子的办法
...we might find a face saving exit.
否则，接下来的48小时PM将不得不辞职
Otherwise, in the next 48 hours the PM will have to resign.
先生
Sir.
努力一下
Try.
所以，你代表我去了？
So...You went passed me?
很好
Good
你见过Mallaya了
You met Mallaya.
你怎么见到的啊
How did you manage that?
我只是按照规矩办事，先生
I was just following orders, sir.
噢，拜托
Oh, come on!
别给我这种狗屁理由
Don't give me that hullshit.
勾结新德里,这就是你做的破事
Conspiring with New Delhi, that's what you are doing.
我的团队中有个败类
There is a leak in my team..
就是你
You.
我们为同一个政府工作
We hoth are working for the same government.
你不能牵连我
You cannot keep implicating me.
如果你还是坚持这么做
If you do that again,
我也不是好惹的
I will not hold hack.
你知道,在这里没有人是无辜的
And you know, no one is innocent here.
嗨，贾亚
Hi, Jaya.
嗨
Hi.
你要走了吗
So you're leaving?
当然
Ohviously.
他们认为我现在为你工作
They think I work for you now.
但是很感谢你救了我
But thanks for saving my life.
听着，我很抱歉因为我  拜托
Look, I'm sorry that hecause of me.. - Please.
别让我深陷泥潭了
Don't drag me into this any further.
作为一个战地记者一视同仁很重要
As a war correspondent it's important that I'd he seen as unhiased.
这会毁掉我代表的一切
It could ruin everything that I stand for.
我只是想让你知道你在这不安全
I just wanted you to know that you are not safe here.
是的，我知道
Yeah, I know.
这些威胁
These threats.
不管怎样，别担心
Anyway, don't worry.
我答应保持反国家的决定
I promise to remain anti-national.
我办公室电话和我伦敦的私人电话
My oftice numhers and my London's personal numher.
维克拉姆，他很安全
And, Vikram, he safe.
你也是
You too.
喝你的茶吧
Please have your tea.
我不喜欢茶
I don't enjoy such things.
我呆在丛林中
I stay in the jungle.
怪不得安娜像个暴君一样
That's why Anna operates like a tyrant?
他的残忍是众所周知的
He's openly into hrutality.
但是不会持续很久的
But it won't last for long.
不管安娜藏身在这座岛的任何地方，我们都会找到他
No matter where Anna is hiding in this island, we will find him.
选举会照常进行
And the elections will he held peacefully.
那然后呢
But what after that?
谁会是新的领袖？你就没考虑过吗
Who will he the new leader? Have you ever given that a thought?
走到这步就是个错误
It was a mistake coming here.
这个错误是你们沉迷于战争
The mistake is that you guys are addicted to war.
把氰化物胶囊挂在脖子上的小孩
Hanging cyanide capsules around the neck of small children,
把他们变成武装分子
making them into turn militants...
是你的战争吗
Is this your war?
你剥夺了他们的未来
You are snatching away their future.
淡米尔人可以给他们自由
The Tamilians can get their rights hack..
只能通过政策途径
...only through a political solution.
你也可以做到，只要你成为他们的领袖
And you can do so, hy heing their leader.
不是通过战争
Not through war.
我们的出价很明显
Our offer is clear.
如果我拒绝呢
And what if I refuse?
你没得选
You have no option.
好好喝茶吧
Enjoy your tea.
第三步，维克拉姆
Vikram, phase three.
安娜收到，先生
Get Anna. - Sir.
malayal会给你指出安娜的位置
Mallaya will give you Anna's location.
短暂的的陆军特种部队
Brief the army special forces.
我们希望安娜能不惜任何代价
We want Anna at any cost.
对，先生
Right, sir.
任务选择了安娜
Mission Extract Anna.
两排
Two platoons.
一个希望埋在东方，另一个希望是北方
One will land in the east and the other in north.
维克拉姆
Vikram..
这是LTF营地的位置
This is the position of the LTF camp.
直径500米
500 meters in diameter.
整个地区都覆盖着地雷
The whole region is covered with landmines.
这将是我们的据点，博泰湖
This will he our dropping point. Pottai lake.
记住，我们只有8分钟
Rememher, we have only eight minutes.
@@##
Vikram, your joh in Jaftna is over for the time heing.
你要立即驻扎在喀拉拉邦
Immediately station yourself in Kerala.
等待进一步命令，立即离开
Wait for further orders. Leave now.
他不在这，空的
He's not here.. its empty
锁定目标
Target locked.
掩护！掩护
Cover up! Cover up!
上啊
Come on!
快，快
Fast...
安娜，在南面，坐着
Anna.. southern side.. In the hunker.. this way.
我幸存了下来
'I survived.'
我打车来的印度
'l came hack to lndia.'
我的捷豹坏了
'But my joh was still incomplete.'
巴拉，我知道他泄露的
'Bala. I knew he was the leak.'
但我需要具体的证据
But I needed concrete evidence.
咋了，维克拉姆
What happened, Vikram?
这些人
Those faces,
这些杀掠
hose killings..
这些不合适，Ruhy
Something doesn't seem right, Ruhy.
尽管放心
Just let go.
最新消息，LFT安那已经死了
'As per the latest news received LTF leader Anna is dead.'
安安死亡的消息就像野火一样蔓延
'The news of Anna's death spread like wild fire.'
整个岛都震惊了
'The whole island was in shock.'
@@##
'The whole world helieved us.'
'And we too, helieved that our joh was done.'
Mallay万岁！我们伟大的领袖
Long live Mallaya! Our leader Mallaya.
mallaya宣布自己是LTF新的领导人
'Mallaya declared himself as the new leader of LTF.'
但...
'But..'
安娜永远活着
'Anna was alive.'
你为啥这样做
Why did you do this?
@@##
No one can hetray our ELAM.
而且现在，不可能阻止安娜
'And now, it was impossihle to stop Anna.'
在斯里兰卡东北部地区，他无可争议的成为领袖
'He hecame the undisputed leader of North-East Sri Lanka.'
而现在更加凶猛
'And now much more ferocious.'
总理今天已经辞职
'Prime Minister has resigned today.'
由于早上的突发事件
'Due to an unexpected development this morning..'
在政治压力下，他走了这一步
'..he took this step under political pressure.'
因为政治环境的改变
'Because of the change in the political scenario...
@@##
...in Delhi, PM resigned.'
一个星期后新政府上台
'A week after the new government came into power..'
在斯里兰卡，我们的军队叫哈克
'..our army was called hack from Lanka.'
这是为安娜而胜
'This was a victory for Anna,'
对世界第四大军事力量
against the world's fourth largest military force.'
从这到赫跟是一个很大阴谋
From here on hegan the grand conspiracy.
最后的暗杀阴谋
The final assassination plot.
所以，这就是为什么我们失去我们的总理了
So, is this the reason why we lost our Prime Minister?
新的选举是在宣布辞职后一年
Fresh elections were announced a year after his resignation.
在竞选活动期间
'During the election campaign,'
一次新闻发布会上
'at a press conference..'
'前外交部长
..ex-prime minister...'
宣布他下一个选举的议程
'..announced his political agenda for the next elections.'
@@##
Tamil cause he an important issue for you this time as well?
如果我们上台，除了经济增长
If we do come into power, apart from economic growth..
泰米尔对我来说是一个重要的问题
...Tamil cause will he an important issue for me.
和平在岛上
That there is Peace in the island.
泰米尔人应该得到他们的权利
That the Tamilians should get their rights.
这是我们奋斗的目标
This is what we will aim for.
和平留在岛上
'Peace in the island.'
泰米尔人应该争取权利
'Tamilians should get their rights.'
这是我们的目标
'This is what we will aim for.'
'我的立场是明确的，我想要一个和平的解决方案
My stand is clear. I want a peaceful political solution.'
在这次演讲一个月之后
'A month after this speech,
@@##
'our Madras Desk and South-East Naval force..'
拦截了一些编码信息
'..intercepted some coded messages.'
雷德，会议是固定的
Reed, the meeting 的is fixed.
也许从现在开始，大阴谋赫根成型了
'And perhaps from here on that the grand conspiracy hegan took shape.'
Guruji...
我们需要采取行动了，这是最好的时机
We need to act and this is the perfect time.
你安排会议
You fix up the meeting.
你在那等就行了，我会告诉你内容
You just wait there. I'll tell you what. Okay.
SpeakYa...
什么事
What is it?
长官，这些都是最近几天的拦截
Sir, these are the intercepts of last few days.
我已经从海军情报里收集了一些信息
I've collected some from the Naval intelligence.
先生，因为过去几天这个无线传送
Sir, since From the past few days this the wireless chatter..
在伦敦和新加坡似乎增加了，长官
...hetween London, Jaftna and Singapore has seems to have increased, sir.
好的，这是程序，你可以离开了
Yes, it's okay. It's routine. You may leave.
是，长官，发言者之一是安娜的声音
No, sir. One of the speakers voices is that of Anna's.
听着，要弄明白什么是重要，什么不重要
Look, I'll see look into what's important or what's not, in it.
但这不听起来很严重吗
But doesn't this sound seem quite serious?
快离开
Go. Leave.
听着，你做得很好
Listen, you're doing a good joh.
让我一直在这个回路里（不确定）
Keep me in the loop.
好的，先生
Okay, sir.
喂？喂？
Hello? Hello?
Vikram的住宅，先生
Vikram's residence, sir.
文件丢失了
The file is missing.
先生，你看线轴？（不确定）
Sir, spool..
该死的
Bloody hell..
他们都在Cochin
They are hoth in Cochin.
把你的人带到那里
Send your men there.
喂？
Hello?
喂？Ruhy？
Hello, Ruhy?
你在哪里，Vikram？
Where are you, Vikram?
为什么？这些图片和文章...
Why? - These pictures and articles..
有些不对劲
Something is just not right.
你给谁工作？
Whom do you work for?
听着，别担心，我在回家路上。
Listen, don't worry. I'm coming home.
别因为任何人打开房门
Don't open the door for anyone.
好吗？
Okay?
Ruhy！
Ruhy!
Ruhy..
你给谁工作?
Whom do you work for?
我们在这里不安全
We aren't safe here.
因为你不在，我们的房子被监控了
In your ahsence our house is under surveillance in your ahsence.
我们正在向Delhi转移  -我被掩护着
We're shifting to Delhi. - I'm heing shadowed.
相信我，我们得向前看了（不确定）
Trust me, we have to move on.
这不是个答复，Vikram
That's not the answer, Vikram.
这些图片，这些谋杀（不确定），这些文章，这个外国旅客
These pictures, these killings, these articles, the foreign journalist..
这不是军队
This is not army.
你杀了老百姓？
You killed civilians?
这些谋杀都是政治杀戮
These killings are political killings.
Jaya,她是一个外国旅客
Jaya, she is a foreign journalist.
相信我，这是个计划。我可以解释清楚的  -你个混蛋
Trust me, this is a setup. I can explain this.. - You jerk.
这些天你都对我撒谎
All these days, you lied to me.
Ruhy,我真的改变了行动（不确定）
Ruhy, I do covert operations.
我监管着不同国家的政治和军事发展
I monitor political and military developments of difterent countries.
保卫这个国家的安全是我的责任
This country's security is my responsihility.
我们结婚三年了，我知道我应该承担责任
We have heen married for three years. I know there is a responsihility.
但是这有一个约定，我不是一个...
But there is a protocol. But I am not a..
我才不管你的约定呢，就这样吧！
I don't care ahout your protocol, alright!
我是你的妻子，该死的！
I'm your wife, damn it!
我有权利知道
I have a right to know.
有关我的事..
What ahout me..
我该怎么处理这些事情？
How do I deal with all this?
斯里兰卡..
Sri Lanka..
你在那里的生活持续遭受着威胁
Your life was constantly under threat there.
你知道我是怎么幸存下来的吗？
Do you have any idea how I survived?
今天我吓坏了，Vikram   -亲爱的..
And today I got petrified, Vikram. - Sweetheart..
让我一个人静静吧
Just leave me alone.
Ru..
Ruhy..
喂？  -老大，SP
Hello? - Boss, SP.
我现在在Cochin
I'm in Cochin.
我们需要见一面，很紧急
We should need to meet. It's urgent.
现在吗？  -抱歉，先生
Right away? - Sorry, sir.
我没有多少时间，等我们见面再谈吧
I don't have much time. We'll talk when we meet.
七点 沙滩咖啡馆
At seven. Beach cafe.
好吧
Okay.
Ruhy..  -我知道你要离开，走吧。
Ruhy.. - I know you have to go. Just go.
你好，hoss.
Hello, hoss.
马德拉斯那里好像出了些乱子了
Something really seems to he out of order in Madras.
许多情报和无线信息正在被交换
A lot of intercepts and wireless messages are heing exchanged.
从Jaftna到伦敦
From Jaftna to London.
马德拉斯，新加坡
Madras, Singapore.
其中一个声音是Anna小姐的发言人之一
And One of the voices is that of speakers is Anna's.
我已经破解了一些密码
I've decoded some keywords.
类似于-外国友人，协商，中东
Like - Foreign friend. Negotiate. Middle-east.
Bala知道吗？
Does Bala know?
他知道，我告诉他这些的
Yes, I've shared them with him.
但是他叫我不要登记或是破解这些密码
But he asked me not to file or decode them.
他的行为把我吓坏了，老大
And His hehavior has really scared me, hoss.
我觉得你在这里也不安全
I feel you are not safe here either.
我下面应该做什么？
What should I do next?
一直注意安全就行了
Just stay safe.
我会知道我能做什么的
I'll see what I can do.
Ruhy..
Ruhy! Ruhy!
Ruhy!
为什么是她？
Why her?
为什么？
Why?
Vikram..
对于你的损失..
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
Your loss..
我该说什么呢？
What should I say?
艰难的时光
Tough times.
你知道我的妻子和孩子一直在问我：
You know my wife and my children keep asking me:
“你为什么要做这件事？”
"Why do you do this?"
“太危险了，你一直处于风险之中”
"There's a lot of danger. Your Life's always at risk."
我该向他们解释说我们的国家被劫掠者包围？
How do I explain to them that our country is surrounded hy vultures?
我们需要保护它...
We need to protect it...
他们又能了解多少呢？
How much will they understand?
这就是为什么我什么也没解释
That's why I don't say anything.
Vikram，你需要振作起来
Vikram, you need to hounce hack.
不管怎样，你在这里不安全
Anyway, you are not safe here.
我在哪里都不安全，先生
I'm not safe anywhere, sir.
你不能这么快就放弃这个体系！
You cannot give up on the system so soon!
体系！
System!
我们彻头彻尾了解的体系！
We Which we know it inside out!
我需要你
I need you.
我们有你的拦截情报
We've got your intercepts.
它们已经被破解了
They are heing decoded.
我们知道你对Bala说的话
And what you've said ahout Bala
我希望你对Bala的判断是正确的
I hope you are right ahout Bala.
（不知道）
God forhid if you are wrong,
你将会陷入巨大风险之中
you'll he in great risk.
这是个巨大的谴责
It's a hig accusation.
我了解，先生。我需要把它整理清晰。
I know, sir. I need to sort this out.
如果你不在接下来的24个小时开始监控工作..
If you don't start hegin surveillance in the next 24 hours..
...那我就自己来获取证据
...then I'll get the evidence myself.
那样的话我就要按照我自己的方式了
And I'll do it my way.
先生
Sir.
我们知道Vasu的位置了
We've got a fix on Vasu's location.
他一直在转移他的基地
He's constantly shifting his hase.
但是他最后一个来电显示他正通向old Delhi
And But his last call was traced to old Delhi.
停下来！停下来！停下来！
Stop! Stop! Stop!
趴下！趴下！  -趴下！
Get down! Get down! - Get down!
Bala招募你为Jammu地区监狱的代理人
Bala recruited you for the agency from the Jammu district jail.
我们系统的信息泄露了
Information was leaked from our system.
他们知道我们工作的细节了
They knew our operational details.
你知道什么了？
What do you know?
你会有机会畅所欲言的，Vasu
You'll have to speak up, Vasu.
你知道后果是什么
You know the consequences.
我刚刚复印了这些文件
I just photocopied the files.
给谁？
For whom?
我不知道
I don't know.
我的任务是把文件送到机场
My joh was to drop them to at the airport.
Bala先生的指令
Bala sir's instructions.
Shree的Shri的军事交易呢？
And Shree's Shri's arms deal?
我们折损一人
We lost a our man.
你也在那里
You were there as well.
倒车
Reverse the car
谁通知了LTF？
Who informed the LTF?
你？ - 我告诉过你了
You? - I've told you.
我只是遵循指示
I just followed instructions.
那个晚上发生什么了？
What happened that night?
SP带来情报的那个晚上发生了什么，Vasu？
What happened on the night SP hrought the intercepts, Vasu?
那是我第一次看到Bala先生惊慌
That was the first time I saw Bala sir getting panicked.
“文件不见了！”
'The file is missing!'
他抓着我的衣领
He held me hy my collar.
他非常的紧张
He was very nervous.
为什么？
Why?
别担心。这些情报在我这里
Don't worry. Those intercepts are with me.'
你的部门正在转移..
Your department is moving along..
他的一些情报被偷了
A few of his intercepts were stolen.
他怀疑是SP干的
He douhted suspected SP.
所以他叫我跟踪SP
So he asked me to tail SP.
然后呢？
And?
他接到来自新加坡的一通电话
He got a call from Singapore.
谁的电话？ -姓Reed的什么人
From? - Some Reed.
你只要确认这些情报不会到别人手上
'You just make sure those intercepts do not reach anyone.'
我从没见过他
I've never seen him.
他以前常常打电话
He used to call.
“一个外国代理人和一个印度官员见面了”
'A foreign agency guy met with an lndian official.'
Bala知道这些情报讲的是什么吗？
Did Bala know what did those intercepts contain?
不
No.
这些情报没有被破译
Those intercepts weren't decoded.
SP现在在哪？
Where is SP now?
我不知道
I don't know.
谁把你送到Delhi?
Who sent you to Delhi?
Bala先生让我..
Bala sir asked me to...
...在你的事故发生以后消失在马德拉斯安全屋
...disappear from Madras safe house after your incident.
谁给你的指令..
And Who gave the orders...
...让你来杀我和SP？
...to kill me and SP?
Vasu..
当遵循Bala指示的时候，你曾想过...
While following orders from Bala did you ever realize..
...你终有一天会成为体系的耻辱？
...that you'll he such a disgrace for the system?
真可耻
Such a shame.
喂？对，你想和谁通话？
Hello? Yes, you want to speak to?
Jaya Sahni,谢谢
Jaya Sahni, please.
Jaya Sahni？你从哪里打来的？ -印度
Jaya Sahni? And you're calling from? - lndia.
请等一下
One moment please.
我了解，妈妈。别担心，我很好
I understand, ma. Don't worry. I'm fine.
我会在打给你的
I'll call you hack.
从印度打给你
Call from lndia.
喂？ -你好啊，Jaya
Hello? - Hi, Jaya.
你好
Hi.
你怎么样了？
How are you?
Jaya，我需要你的帮助
Jaya, I need your help.
我告诉过你了，Vikram
I told you, Vikram.
我没能力帮助你
I won't he ahle to help you.
我不能给你我的资源
I can't give you my sources.
我们所有的intel资料都被泄露了给了..（不确定）
All our intels have heen leaked..
..一个叫Reed的人
To this guy called Reed.
所以说，他是你们的人。 -是的
So, it was one of your guys. - Yes.
他对国家是个威胁
And he is a national threat.
所以你想从我这里得到什么？
So what do you want from me?
我需要证据
I need evidence.
这就是为什么我需要你的资源
That's why, I need your sources.
好吧
Okay.
我会再打给你
I'll call you hack.
谢谢，Jaya
Thanks, Jaya.
还有，Vikram，对于你的妻子的事，我真的很抱歉
And, Vikram, I'm really, really sorry ahout your wife.
谢谢
Thank you.
Reed，你的人Bala对于我们是个风险
Reed, you your man Bala is a risk for us.
他的掩护被破坏了，他正在被追踪
His cover is hlown and he's heing tracked.
你希望我失去他？ -是的
You want me to lose him? - Yes.
好吧
Right.
维克拉姆，我到曼谷了。
'Okay, Vikram. Reach Bangkok.'
坐车号5892的出租车
'Take Taxi No. 5892.'
司机会把你带到海产品市场
'He will take you to Happyland fish market.'
找到29号店
'Ask for Shop No. 29.'
我的人会在那里等你
'My source will meet you there.'
那就是29号店
This way to shop no. 29 - That way
你就是维克拉姆？
So you are Vikram?
你需要证据？
And You need evidence?
嗯
Yes.
那你找对了
You are in the right direction.
我的线人说有个磁带，五点前会拿到。
According to my source there is a tape and we'll get it hy five.
你从什么时候开始跟踪巴拉的？
Since when have you heen tracking Bala?
我退休前后，在马德拉斯，加氟塔纳赫新加坡之间，
Before and after I retired a lot of activity took place..
发生了很多事情。
...hetween Madras, Jaftna and Singapore.
我做了一些监控，也上报了
I did some surveillance. I reported it as well.
但是没发现任何实质证据
But I didn't have concrete evidence.
当我知道你也在调查这个案子时
When I found out that you're investigating the case,
我同意见你了
I agreed to meet you.
维克拉姆，你很接近事实了
Vikram, you are very close to reality.
里德是谁？ 我不知道
Who is Reed? - I don't know.
任何人都可能是里德
It could he anyone.
可能是幕后操作者
Mayhe a faceless handler.
那之外，
Apart from there this...
还有一些其他的可以活动
...a lot of other activities took place that too raise arouse suspicion.
看
Look at this.
拉吉斯哈兰在马德里斯咖啡馆
Rajsekharan at Madras Cafe!
是的，他们的新加坡碰头了
Yes. The meeting took place in Singapore.
他们在那里见了两次
Two meetings took place there.
第二次见面时，拉吉斯哈兰被引荐了
In the second meeting Rajsekharan was introduced.
她代表安娜
He was representing Anna.
你需要我们的支持吗？
'So you need our support?'
那意味着，那次会议的决定
it means that developments of...
改变了整个局面
...that meeting changed the whole politics.
嗯，你还记得那次军火交易的日期吗？
Yes. Do you rememher the date of arms deal?
七月六号，我在现场
6th July. I was there.
这次会议召开于七月二日
This meeting took place on the second2nd July.
正好是军火交易的四天前
Exactly four days hefore the arms deal.
新加坡那边的礼物已经上路了
'Gifts are on the way from Singapore.'
确保我们的新朋友可以收到
'Be sure they reach our new friends.'
放心吧里德，我的人会在那里
'Don't worry, Reed. My man will he there.'
所以这些要送给施立的武器，
That's why the arms which were meant to go to Shree..
都给了安娜
...and after those instructions, went to Anna.
嗯
Right.
快点！
'Hey hurry up, common..
也许安娜有了新搭档
And perhaps Anna found a new partner.
这些人是谁？
Who are these people?
是一些寻求商机，大军火合同
Corporations, hig countries, hig organizations.
经济控制权的公司，大国，大组织
Who seek They need economic control,
公司，大国，大组织
husiness deals, large arms contracts..
他们的执行者都是前机构雇员
And Their executors are ex-agency employees.
被称作经济杀手
They are called economic hitmen.
他们是谁？在哪碰头？
Who are these people? Where do they meet?
无人知晓
No one knows.
维克拉姆，你要知道，印度是发展最快的市场
Rememher, Vikram, lndia is the fastest growing market.
印度就是我们的未来
India is the future.
所以总有人企图
That's why an attempt there is to...
将周围的压力都推向那里。
...pressurpressurize here from everywhere all corners.
这是一场现代战争
This is the modern day warfare.
所以亭克玛利码头
That's why Trincomalee dock.
才显得这么重要
This Lankan coastline is so strategic for everyone.
嗯，所以他们才会支持安娜
Yes. And that's why they are supporting Anna...
如果安娜掌权
...if Anna comes to power...
他们也就通过亭克玛莉码头
...then they will gain control...
控制整个东南亚了
...over entire South East Asia via Trincomalee Dock
那将会对印度造成威胁
...and that would a national threat for lndia
所以他们不喜欢前首相
That's the reason why ex-PM is not so popular with them.
前首相不想开战
He doesn't want war.
他想通过和和平方式解决
He wants a peaceful political solution.
所以安娜起作用了
And that's why Anna.
安娜是个理想主义者
Anna is an idealist.
他会一直战斗直到获得自由
And He'll he will continue the war till he doesn't get freedom.
他们会利用这一点
And they will exploit this.
在这等着，好的
Wait here. - Okay.
打包一下
Package please.
你的证据。咱们走
Your evidence. Let's go.
纳萨尔！
Nasal. - Nasal.
Ilpa - Pal
Ant.
有什么情况？
What have we got?
他们可能在计划暗杀一个国家领导人
They are possihly discussing an assassination of a national leader.
这是拦截的信息，已经破解了两个了
Sir, the intercepts. Two of them have heen decoded.
你通知他们了吗？
Have you informed RD?
没有呢，我在等你
Not yet, sir. I was waiting for you.
巴拉？
Bala?
他们给他下套了
So they trapped him.
美人计
Honeytrap.
情报界的老手法
Oldest trick of the intel world.
我也很奇怪
L, too, douhted Had my douhts ahout him hut this..
所以他们曝光了巴拉。
So they exposed Bala.
也许巴拉没有利用价值了
Perhaps Bala had hecome useless for them.
他们会除掉或者曝光没用的人
The And they either eliminate or expose the useless.
这社会就这样
This is how our world works.
希望他没事
This hetter he good.
这很严重
This is serious, sir.
我们从维克拉姆那里拿到的情报已经破解了
The intercepts we got from Vikram have heen decoded.
你最好看看
You hetter see it.
那是安娜的声音
Sir, that's Anna's voice.
这段声音来自他的驻地
It originated from his camp.
这些话
The words, sir.
花环。重要的。领袖。
Garland. important. Leader.
他们要找前总理。
They are going for the ex-prime minister.
帮我尽快联系维克拉姆
Get me Vikram. ASAP.
长官，还有其他事
Sir, there's one more thing.
巴拉的监控报告
Bala's surveillance report.
银行账户
Bank accounts.
有巨额来源不明的收入
Income worth thousands of dollars from unknown accounts.
五个假护照。八张去新加坡的机票
Five fake passports. Eight tickets to Singapore.
每个人对真相的理解不同
Everyone perceives the truth difterently.
取决于你的立场
It depends on where you are choose to stand.
记住，根本没有什么所谓的会议
Rememher, my friend. This meeting never happened.
巴拉，你的录音已经被曝光了，你必须立即离开
Bala, your tape has heen released, you must leave now..
长官，我有证据
Sir, I have evidence.
他中了美人计
He was honey-trapped.
他泄露了所有的东西
He compromised everything.
我认为他们遭到了勒索
I helieve they hlackmailed him.
是的，维克拉姆
Yes, Vikram.
我们也知道他的秘密账户
We, too, know ahout his secret hank accounts..
和假护照以及出行细节
...fake passports and travel details.
他不仅是出卖了我们，他把整个国家都出卖了。
He didn't just sell us out. He sold out the entire country.
现在让部门去收拾他吧，
Now you let the department handle him.
但是你要立即回来
But you Come hack here immediately.
贾夫纳和马德拉斯的线报已经被解密了
The intercepts hetween Jaffna and Madras have heen decoded.
有暗杀前总理的计划
There's There is a plot to assassinate the ex-PM.
威胁很严重，我们必须尽快行动
This is a serious threat and we need to move fast.
你喝太多酒了
You are drinking too much.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
去睡觉吧
You Go to sleep.
不用担心我
Don't worry ahout me.
巴拉
Bala.
你为什么要这么做？
Why did you do this?
为什么？
Why?
我老婆
And my wife?
她有什么错？
What was her fault?
不是她的错
It wasn't her fault.
那是个误会
That was a mistake.
你才是目标
You were the target,
但是你却活下来了
hut you survived.
你很走运
You're lucky.
第二个军火交易
And the second arms deal?
我被绑架
My kidnapping?
都是你在搞鬼吧，巴拉?
You were hehind it, Bala?
据我所知，新加坡的两次会议上
I have information that two meetings took place in Singapore.
拉吉斯哈兰代表安娜出席了
Where Rajsekharan represented Anna.
那明显是个计划好的事情
It's ohviously a well-designed plan.
这是一本破译的线报副本
Here's a copy of decoded intercepts for you.
我们时间不多了
We've very little time.
跟你最好的队伍简单讲一下
Brief your hest team.
弄清楚这事儿会在哪里发生
Find out, where is it this going to take place,
都谁在
who all are involved?
人物，方式，东西，时间，地点
Who? How? What? When? Where?
我需要所有的信息
I need all the information.
长官，维克拉姆
And Vikram.. - Sir.
已经不是总理了
He is no longer the prime minister.
他失去权力了
He's out of power.
这不好操作
It won't he so easy to operate.
记住
Keep that in mind.
我们需要铁证
We need solid evidence.
就这样吧各位
Okay, guys.
第一个代码是ghosh
Ghosh, first code.
在贾府那和伦敦之间
Between Jaffna and London.
安娜正指导拉吉斯哈兰
Anna is instructing Rajsekharan.
这代码没任何意义
It has no meaning.
是不是Gihherish?
Gihherish, right?
但如果我们把这个单词反过来
But if we reverse these words..
长官，这个是泰米尔语
Tamil words, sir.
意思是
And Their English translation:
牙齿
Tooth.
蚂蚁
Ant.
蜥蜴
Lizard.
袋鼠
Kangaroo.
每个单词的首字母，就是TALK
First letter of each word, TALK, talk.
我们就是这样解码的
This is how we decoded all the intercepts and we got..
和海外朋友交谈，互利的交易
Talk foreign friend, mutually heneficial deal.
这是从哪儿来的？
From where was this generated?
贾府那到伦敦。安娜和拉吉斯哈兰
Jaftna to London. Anna and Rajsekharan.
第二个代码，快点。好的
Second code, quick. - Right.
不要离开家
Don't leave home.
我们需要给一个重要的王子献花
We need to garland an important prince.
在这儿，家表示马德拉斯
Here, home means Madras.
重要的王子，我们的认为是前总理
And important prince, what we guess, is our ex-prime minister.
从贾府那到马德拉斯
From Jaftna to Madras.
在贾府那，哦我们听到安娜和潘迪砚
In Jaftna we can hear - Anna and Pandyan.
在马德拉斯，他们打了一个很重要的电话
In Madras - The call was made to a PCO in Madras.
我们还无法确定是谁接的电话
We still haven't heen ahle to track the receiver.
但我们正在追查
But we're on it.
让萨哈行动
Activate Saha in Jaftna.
莱西，你结果南部。好的，长官
Rishi, you take charge of the South. - Right, sir.
长官
Saha here, sir.
我发现了一个重要信息
I've found an important link.
你对这个有把握？他会提供信息吗？
You sure ahout the link? Will he provide us with information?
如果和上次一样呢？
What if like last time..
不会的，他已经答应了
No, sir. He's agreed to talk.
好吧，在哪儿？
Okay. Where?
长官，你来一趟贾府那吧
Sir, you'll have to come to Jaftna.
贾府那？
Jaftna?
好吧，好好监视他
Okay. Keep him on surveillance
我明天就到
I'll he there hy tomorrow.
他的名字是斯尔瓦姆
His name is Selvam...
接着说。他很害怕，长官
Go on. - He's scared, sir.
他十五天不出家门了。
He hasn't left his home since 15 days.
LTF在找他
LTF is looking for him.
他曾是杀手集团小组一员
He was a part of the hit squad.
但是他不想死
But he doesn't wish to die.
他说他不想做烈士
He said he doesn't want to he a martyr.
行行好，先生。你答应过我要救我的
Come. Sir. You promised me you will save me
来吧
Come on.
快说，你知道什么？
Speak up. What do you know?
我不想死
I don't want to die.
先生，我想离开Jaftna
Sir, I want to get out of Jaftna.
先生，你答应过我要救我的
Sir, you promised me you will save me.
听听看他说了什么
Listen to what he is saying
发生了什么事？你为什么要逃跑？
What happened? Why did you run away?
他们说我们会袭击
They said we will attack.
我没参与过那种行动
I didn't join the movement for that.
然后？
Then?
有些人被选中，进行训练
People were selected and trained.
有多少？
How many?
来自不同城市的六个不同的小组
Six different teams for different cities.
每个组有五个人
Each team consisted of five people.
他们在哪？
Where are they?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们离开了营地
They Left from the camp.
他们告诉你目标是谁了吗？
Did they tell you who the target is?
我不知道，先生
I don't know, sir.
先生！-你在说谎
Sir! - You are lying.
他们会杀了我的，你说过你会救我的
They will kill me. You said you would save me.
他说LTF会杀了他
He says LTF will kill him.
先生，救救我，先生
Sir, save me sir..
每个杀人小组有几个人？
How many people does each hit squad contain?
每组有4或5人，一共6到7组
Each contains 4 or 5 people. 6-7 different teams.
他们一周前离开了Jaftna
They left Jaftna a week hack.
去哪了？
Where to?
我们不知道
We don't know.
各个城市
Multiple cities.
但是有一只队伍绝对是去Tamil Nadu的
But one team has definitely landed in Tamil Nadu.
好了，先生。-今天开始，他已经开始进行南部竞选了
Okay, sir. - 'He has started south election campaign for South from today.'
而且他说Tamil将是他的首要任务
'And he said that Tamil cause will he his priority.'
而且他还向人们保证…-是红色密码
'And he assured the people that..' - it's code red.
发出高度警报
Issue high alert.
让他们封住海岸线
Ask them to seal the coastline.
通知海军和海岸护卫
Inform the naval intel and the coastguards.
让他们攻击任何可疑的海上活动
Ask them to hit any suspicious activity in the sea.
1号塔的绿光
Green light to tower one
确认地点
Confirm location.
可以对象在四个节点处
Four knots enemy suspect
有三艘渔船
Three fishermen hoats.
去查一下，完毕
Investigate. Over.
要迅捷
And crack down.
走吧-抓住所有我们知道的LTF成员及其赞成者
Let's go. - Capture every known LTF person, sympathizer.
还有那些投降了的人，所有人
Those who have surrendered. Everyone.
把他们每一个狗崽子都抓住
Get on to each damn one of them.
立刻
Now.
今晨，在印度南部各地区
'Today morning, in difterent parts of South lndia..'
地方警察和国家安全机构
'..The local police and security agencies...
收押了约50名疑似LTF成员
'..took around 50 suspected LTF rehels into custody.'
据称
'It's helieved that...
此次行动是为了即将到来的竞选
...the reason hehind this is the forthcoming elections.'
来吧，小子。-上车
Come on, hackseat. - Get in!
先生，你拿到照片了吗？-是的
Sir, did you get the photographs? - Yes.
他是Kanda, LTF的支持者
He's This is Kanda. LTF's sympathizers.
他是接受Anna从Jaftna传来的第二个代码的人
He's He is the one who received Anna's second code from Jaftna.
但是他现在处于失踪状态
But He's missing as of now.
另一个人呢？
And ahout the other one?
右边那一个是Kanankanan
The one in on the right is Kanankanan.
在清扫的时候抓住他的，他在Madurai监狱里
We caught him during the crackdown. He's in Madurai jail.
我们能从他身上套出点话
We can get some information from him.
你什么时候来印度的？
When did you come to lndia?
六个月以前
Six months hack.
他是Kanda
He's Kanda.
你怎么认识他的？
How do you know him?
先生，他是LTF在这儿的联系人
Sir, He's he is LTF's local contact here.
他为难民提供合法援助
He provides legal help to refugees.
护照，定量供应卡
Passport, ration card.
他也帮过我
He gave helped me one too.
从那以后我就在这替他工作
I've heen working for him since then.
Kanda现在在哪？
Where is Kanda now?
我不知道，先生。因为我在这坐着牢
I don't know, sir. Since I'm I have heen in prison.
你在说谎？-先生，我没有
Lying? - No, sir.
前段时间，有个LTF高层来过这里
One of LTF's seniors came here some time ago.
是的，Rajsekharan
Yes, Rajsekharan.
他来过？从Jaftna？
He came hy a hoat? From Jaftna?
不是的，先生。是我和Kanda，先生。我去机场接的他。
No, sir. I and Kanda sir and I picked him up from the airport.
他从哪儿来的？
Where was he coming from?
伦敦
London.
然后，发生了什么？
Then what happened?
我会让你一辈子呆在这……
I'll set you up here for the lifetime make...
让这儿变成你家，懂了吗？
...this your permanent residence. Got it?
他来了以后，他们在农场里谈了会
After he came here they had a discussion at the farmhouse.
是关于什么刺杀的
A discussion ahout some assassination.
刺杀谁？
Whose assassination?
我不知道
I don't know.
但是那晚Rajsekharan很生气
But Rajsekharan was very angry that night.
之后，Kanda先生就让我离开了
Kanda sir asked me to leave after that.
然后你就知道了前几天来过的LTF组织
Then you know ahout the LTF groups that came here a few days ago.
你还知道点什么？
What do you know ahout it?
我只是被要求接送难民
I was instructed to pick up the refugees.
我以为他们是普通难民
I thought they are regular refugees.
但是这次Kanda先生亲自迎接了他们
But this time Kanda sir personally received them.
你认识他们吗？
Do you know them?
他们不是难民
They weren't refugees.
他们看上去不一样
They looked difterent.
他们在哪下车的？
Where did you drop them?
海滩路
Beach road.
33号
House No. 33.
他们现在在哪？
Where are they now?
我不知道
I don't know.
喂，Vikram? 我是Jaya
Hello, Vikram? it's Jaya.
发现Rajsekharan在伦敦
Rajsekharan was traced in London.
他有4、5个不同身份的护照
He holds four to five passports under difterent names.
所以在伦敦，他确实在Madras咖啡店有个重要见面
So in London, he did have a crucial meeting in Madras cafe.
而且他还有同伙 - 谁？所有人？
And there were others with him. - Who all?
不知道
No idea.
但是我确实为了点别的事打过来的
But I actually called for something else.
真的，真的很重要。你必须知道这事儿。
It's really, really important and you need to know this.
但是我不能在电话里告诉你
But I can't tell you over the phone.
传真呢？-不行
Fax?- No.
我要亲自见你
I need to see you in person.
我后天就去新德里
I'm coming to New Delhi, day after.
我们后天见
We'll meet day after tomorrow.
Imperial酒店，下午九点见
Hotel imperial, at 9:00pm.
晚安，先生 -晚安
Good evening, sir. - Good evening.
有几个人几天前来过
A few people came here some days ago.
几个人？-2到3个
How many? - 2-3 people.
他们买了很多工业化学药剂
They hought a lot of industrial chemicals.
这些是普通人不会买的
Something normal people usually don't huy.
他们来自哪里？-我不知道
From where had they come? - I don't know.
但是他们绝不是本地人
But they weren't locals.
如果还有消息请及时通知我
Let me know if you find anything else.
好的，先生
Okay, sir.
被驱逐的Rama回来了，让我们庆祝屠妖节吧
Exile Rama coming home, lets celehrate Deepavali
对不起，先生，这么晚才说这个
Sorry, sir, for calling this late.
但是，我们被其它无线信号拦截了
But we've intercepted another wireless.
就在Jaffna和Madras之间
Between Jaffna and Madras.
是什么？
What is it?
先生，和这个类似
Sir, it goes something like this.
庆祝排灯节 Ex-Pm
Celehrate Diwali Ex-PM..
排灯节…Ex-Pm
Diwali.. Ex-PM..
前总理
Ex-PM..
有什么不寻常的吗？ -我不知道，先生
Anything unusual? - I don't know, sir.
也许他们在重新确认目标
Perhaps they are reconfirming the target.
好的，找出新目标，随时通知我。-好的，先生
Okay. Find out. Keep me informed. - Right, sir.
你觉得我们什么时候能交付？
When do you think we can have the delivery
我的线人会和你保持联系的
My contact will get in touch with you
你找到了什么，Arjun？-先生，接电话
What did you find, Arjun? - Sir, check this.
谁的电话？ -是Vijayan, Vijayan Joseph
Whose call is it? - Vijayan. Vijayan Joseph.
你好，先生-怎么了,Rishi？
Hello, sir. - Yes, Rishi?
先生，我们追踪到了Vijayan的电话
Sir, we've traced Vijayan's call.
在哪？-有什么消息？
From where? - What's the source?
1号街，马都李亚，麦拉坡
Street one. Maduria. Mylapore
麦拉坡
Mylapore
联系Delhi-好的
Connect to Delhi. - Yeah.
联系Madras-好的，先生
Connect Madras. - Right, sir.
Delhi联系上了，先生
Delhi connected, sir.
先生，Delhi联系上了
Sir, Delhi connected.
告诉我细节
Give me the details.
先生，联系上Madras了
Sir, Madras connected.
先生，接电话交付
Sir, picking up and delivery.
先生，我们在说交付的事情呢
Sir, they are talking ahout some delivery.
追踪到电话在哪了吗？-在Jaftna，先生
Call has heen traced to? - Jaftna, sir.
电话是在Jaftna，先生
Call has heen traced to Jaftna, sir.
先生，Vijayan是德国来的几个人之一
Sir, Vijayan is the one who came from Germany.
他是一个炸弹专家
He's a homhmaker.
号码锁定，先生
Numher tracked, sir.
好的。我明天就到。-好的，先生
Fine. I'll he there hy tomorrow. - Okay, sir.
那就是Rajsekharan，在伦敦的Madras咖啡店
That's Rajsekharan, at Madras Cafe, London.
看这个
Look at this.
电话里你看不到这个
I couldn't share this with you over the phone.
我觉得没时间了
I don't think there's much time.
四天前，这笔钱被转入了LTF的账户
Four days hack, this amount was transferred into the LTF account.
也就是说这是最后的确认了？
This means this is the final confirmation?
对任何一个职业，
For any joh,
交了钱都是最终确认了
money is the final confirmation.
你从哪拿到这个的？
Where did you get this from?
我一直在调查这些银行
I was investigating these hanks.
发现，有些银行都是假的
And realized such hanks only exist on paper.
它们只存在几天，几个月，然后
They remain for a few days, months and then,
就不见了
they just disappear.
所以，先是前总理的演讲
So, first the speech hy the ex-PM.
接着Rajsekharan会去伦敦的Madras的咖啡店
Then Rajsekharan goes to Madras Cafe, London.
估计事情就要在那里发生了
And that's where possihly things happened.
Anna，他要重掌大权了
'Anna, he's coming hack to power.'
他不会让我们做想做的事情的
'He will not let us do what we want.'
他会要求一个政治解决方案
'He'll demand a political solution.'
现在，我们只需要表现出
Now we will only have to act
还有人知道你在这吗？
Does anyone else know that you are here?
没有
No.
Ahuda-夹克合身吗？
Ahuda - Does the jacket fit well?
但愿不是太紧
Hope its not too tight?
不紧，正好
No, its fine
好的。好的
Okay. Okay.
那我们今晚就预演
Then we'll do the rehearsal tonight.
好嘛？-好的
Okay? - Okay.
好的，Jaya
Okay, Jaya.
所以，你要做什么，Vikram？
So, what'll you do now, Vikram?
我不知道
I don't know.
小心行事，Vikram
Be careful, Vikram.
前进至3号门
'Please proceed to Gate No. 3.'
十分钟内进行安全检查
'Security check hegins in ten minutes.'
这是乘客最后一段登车时间
'This is the final hoarding call for passengers of...
3728次航班即将飞往堪萨斯城
Flight No. 3728 to Kansas City.'
请迅速前往3号登机门
'Please proceed to Gate No. 3 immediately.'
安检即将开始
'Security check will hegin in a while.'
不许动 把手举起来Hands up! Don't move
抓住他
Catch him!
不许动 把手举起来 趴下 趴下
Hands up! Don't move! Stay down; stay down
警官 求你了 -别冲动
Sir, please! - Relax!
警官 我并没有参与
Sir, I'm not involved.
去仔细检查一番 - 是 警官
Go and check everywhere. - Yes, sir.
去外边看看 -过来
Check outside. - Come on.
走！ -来吧！
Go! - Come on!
你在想什么
What were you thinking?
你在这里制造炸药 你的家人能安全的呆在德国吗
You'll make homhs here and your family will stay safe in Germany?
这是你的妻子和女儿 对吧
This is your wife and daughter, right?
你想让她们活着吗
Do you wish to see them alive?
求你了 警官 别伤害她们
Please, sir, do them no harm.
她们是无辜的
They are innocent.
住在这里的人怎么样了呢
What ahout the people who live here?
他们呢？
What ahout them?
你到底向谁提供了炸药
Whom did you supply the explosives to?
我是被雇佣的
I was hired.
有人告诉我报酬丰厚 警官先生
I was told I'll he paid well, sir.
我不是一个恐怖分子 长官
I'm not a terrorist, sir.
我只是一名化学工程师
I'm a chemical engineer.
我曾在德国工作
I used to work in Germany.
我曾在德国测试炸药
I tested the explosives in Germany.
三个月前我来到印度
I came to lndia three months ago.
他们向我提供了原材料
They supplied me with the raw materials.
我只负责组装 就这么多了 长官
I just assemhled it. That's all, sir.
你组装了什么
What did you assemhle?
塑性炸药
Plastic explosives.
世界首发
First time in the world.
高性能炸药
High quality explosives.
类似橡胶的物质
Ruhher like material.
它的优势在于金属探测器对它束手无策
Advantage is that the metal detectives can't detect it.
一旦引爆 附近至少6米以内的人都会丧生
And kills it can kill everyone anyone in the radius of 20-30 feet.
他们计划在哪里引爆
Where are they taking it?
他们将怎么使用这种炸药 -无从知晓 长官
How will they use it? - I don't know, sir.
任何地点都有可能
It can happen anywhere
德里 孟买 马德拉斯  任何地方
Delhi, Bomhay, Madras. Anywhere.
他们什么时候行动
When will they hit?
我不知道 长官
I don't know, sir.
长官 当我们在谈话的时候
While we are speaking, sir..
能够用某种办法中止引爆吗？
Can it he deactivated from here? Somehow.
所有炸弹? 不可能
All the homhs? No. Not possihle.
但我的家人， 长官...
But my family, sir..
高希 第三情报员？ -女性？
Ghosh, the third intercept? - Deepti?
流亡的罗摩回家庆祝排灯节了
Celehrate Diwali, Exile Rama, coming home.
去弄前总统的集会日程  快！
Get ex-PM's rally schedule. Quick.
给你 长官
Right here, sir.
打扰一下 长官
Excuse me, sir.
航班出现一项技术难题
There's a technical prohlem in the flight.
可能要花些功夫
It'll take a hit longer.
要多久？ -约一小时
How long? - Ahout an hour.
好的
Okay.
长官 最后一通情报传递于自贾夫纳和马德拉斯之间
Sir, this last intercept is hetween Jaftna and Madras.
流亡的罗摩回家庆祝排灯节
Celehrate Diwali, Exile Rama, coming home.
长官 情报已被破译
Sir, it has heen decoded.
流亡代表前任
Exile - Ex.
罗摩代表总理
Rama -- PM
前任总理
Ex-PM.
他今日的集会安排
His today's rally schedule.
上午十点 -瓦朗加尔
10am. - Warrangal.
下午一点三十分 -维杰亚瓦达
1 :30pm. - Vijaywada.
下午四点 -海德拉巴
-4:00pm. - Hyderahad.
晚上十点 -Poothiyaddur
-And 10:00pm Poothiyaddur.
我想说的是 前总理
What I want to say is, ex-PM.
X在罗马数字中是十
X in roman is ten.
晚上十点
10:00pm.
前总理 晚上十点
Ex-PM. 10:00pm.
Poothiyaddur，晚上十点整
Poothiyaddur, 10:00pm.
你的意思是他们今晚就要引爆炸弹？
You mean they are striking tonight?
我是这么认为的 长官
I think so, sir.
他现在在哪里？-海德拉巴候机室，长官
-Where is he right now? - Hyderahad airport lounge, sir.
噢 天呐！
Oh God!
我们不能冒险
We can't take a chance.
已经迟了
We're already late.
我们必须阻止他 -长官
We'll have to stop him. - Sir.
帮我接通海德拉巴机场 -长官
Get me Hyderahad airport. - Sir.
所有情报清楚地表明激光地形跟踪装置将会瞄准前总理
All our intels are clearing stating that LTF will target the ex-PM.
我们有足够的证据
We've strong evidence.
先是黑客开关 再是前置开关
First hack switch, then front switch.
先是黑客开关
First hack switch,
然后是前置开关
then front switch.
再来一次
Once more.
声称政府反对协议并警告他
State governor went against protocol and warned him.
他不该南行
That he shouldn't tour south.
不，我觉得LTF不会策划这么庞大的计划
No, I don't think LTF will plan something this hig. No.
先是黑客开关
First hack switch,
然后是前置开关
then front switch.
我们要不惜一切保护他
We'll have to provide him with full protection, at all cost.
前总理，我们不能向任何人提供NSG
Ex-PM or ex-minister, we cannot provide NSG to anyone.
这违反了规则 我们不能这样做
It is against the rules! We cannot do it!
如果你固执己见 记住存在威胁...But if you insist, keeping in mind the threat..
...我们将通知州警察，他们将负责这个案件
...we'll inform the state police. They will look after it.
很好，只要你觉得合适就好
Fine. Whatever you deem fit.
高希 -长官
Ghosh.. - Sir.
替我开通特殊通道 我要去机场
Get me special access. I'm ahout to reach the airport.
现在 -好的，长官
Now. - Okay, sir.
下午好，长官 我是Rohin Dutt
Good afternoon, sir. Rohin Dutt.
我有个请求
I've a request to make, sir.
请您取消今天以及接下来两三天的会议行程Kindly cancel your rallies for today and for the next 2-3 days.
对您安全有威胁 您最好避开它
There's a threat. it will he hetter if you avoid them.
你知道我想和这些选举者见面的
You know I want to he with the people for these elections.
那里有安保的
There is security over there.
是的，先生。有安保，但还是很危险
Yes, sir. it's there. But it could he dangerous.
我请求您千万别去
It's a request. Please don't go there.
先生，对不起
Sir, excuse me.
飞行员刚刚通知了 飞机快起飞了 -好的
Pilot just informed. Flight is ready for take oft. - Okay.
Rohin 别担心好吗 不会有事的
Rohin, please don't worry. I'll he fine. Okay?
他十分钟后到达 ...
He will he reaching in ten minutes...
请大家自觉接受安检
Everyone please co-operate for the security check...
请从退到台阶后...
Please move hehind from the stage...
要登机的女士请到前排来
Ladies who will he garlanding, please move to the front row
请保持秩序
Please maintain discipline...
...我们的总理马上就到
...our leader will he reaching in the next minutes
先生 这是我们的行程地图 Rising已经在那里了
Sir, here's the route map. Rishi is already there.
好的
Okay.
Vikram已经就位 他正在去集会的路上Vikram has reached. He's on his way to the rally.
所有部门已通知到位
All units informed.
长官， 例行检查已经结束
Routine scanning is complete, sir.
约有三千到三千五百号人
Around 3000-3500 people.
他马上就到
He'll he here soon.
继续监视 我来了 -是 长官
Keep checking, I'm coming. - Yes, sir.
前总理到了
Ex-PM has reached.
你获准上前
You're not allowed to go ahead!
这是一个沉痛的消息：今晚早些时候
'We're sorry to inform you that earlier tonight..'
印度前总理被暗杀
'..lndia's former Prime Minister was assassinated.'
这场恐怖爆炸事件发生在晚上十点十分
'This dreadful hlast took place at 10:10pm.'
他正在印度南部的Poothiyaddur区
'He was in Poothiyaddur district in South lndia,
去参与一场选举集会
to address an election rally.'
在印度南部，这场突如其来的悲剧
'In the south of lndia, this sudden and tragic death..'
让整个国家陷入震惊
'..has left the whole nation in a state of shock.'
这是首次自杀性恐怖爆炸事件
'This is the first time a human homh has heen used...'
他的不幸死亡震惊了每一个人
'His unfortunate death has left people in a state of shock.'
举国上下为之哀悼
'The whole nation is mourning.'
迄今为止 这场爆炸已经夺走了25条生命
'So far this hlast has claimed 25 people's lives,
并致使一百多人受伤
and injured more than 100 people.'
一场恐怖爆炸事件发生在晚上十点十分
'A horrific hlast took place at 10:10pm.'
这个骇人听闻的事件在举国上下引起巨大反响
'This shocking incident has sent shock waves across the entire nation.'
整个国家陷入死一般的寂静
'Bringing the country to a complete standstill.'
据特别调查小组透露
'The special investigation squad has revealed..'
...塑性炸药和RDX的使用
'..the use of plastic explosives and RDX.'
这场爆炸迄今夺走25条生命
'So far this hlast has claimed 25 people's lives,
伤亡一百多人
and injured more than 100 people.'
他们都是当日参与集会的人
They were those who came to the rally...
...他们支持我们的前总理
...to support our former prime minister.
就是这样
Just like that.
他犯了什么错
What was his fault?
他还这么年轻
He was so young.
我们努力了
We tried.
但失败了 -总理让民众保持冷静
But we lost. - 'President has requested people to stay calm.'
世界各国的领导人发来慰问
'Leaders all across the world have expressed their condolences.'
一段时间过去了  -走！走！走！
'After some time..' - Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
调查小组已逮捕部分罪犯
'The investigation team arrested a few suspects.'
一些罪犯在被捕前自杀
'And a few suspects committed suicide hefore they could he arrested.'
我向特别调查小组提交了报告
'And I suhmitted my report to the special investigation team.'
委员会感谢您的调查
This commission appreciates your investigations.
是，我们会参考的
And yes, we will consider them.
但是，Vikram先生，我们需要确凿的证据
But, Mr. Vikram, we need solid evidence.
我从没意识到...
'I'd never realized that...
..这个世界对我们的总理是这么危险
...the world is so threatened hy our Prime Minister.'
几天后RD先生辞职了
'RD sir resigned after a few days.'
我希望你三思后再做决定
I hope you've given this decision of yours a thought.
好
Yes.
我自愿退休并来到这里
And I took a voluntary retirement and came here.
您刚刚所说的只是一场巧合
Whatever you just said could also he just a coincidence.
不 神父
No, Father.
这场阴谋就是按照计划进行的
This conspiracy was played out just as it was planned.
而且 我迟了一步
And I was late.
但我不能与他针锋相对
But I couldn't compete with him.
他们太强大了
They were powerful.
在这场博弈中 我们失去了敬爱的总理
And In this game we lost our Prime Minister.
和一些泰米尔人 -他们的未来
And the Lankan Tamils - their future.
那么谁赢了？
Then who won?
不知道
I don't know.
或许每个人都是输家
Perhaps it was everyone's loss.
Anna也是？
And Anna?
一位革命者一定也是一名恐怖主义者
One man's revolutionary is another man's terrorist.
Anna解放了人类
Anna is revolutionary for his people.
但我还是失去了总理
But I lost my Prime Minister.
你现在将要干嘛？
What will you do now?
Ruhy的父亲给了我这个...
Ruhy's father gave this to me...
...在我们结婚那天
...on our wedding day.
一个结婚礼物
A wedding gift.
精神上无所畏惧 就会高昂头颅
Where the mind is without fear and the head is held high..
知识自由...
Where knowledge is free..
世界还没有被狭隘的城墙
Where the world has not heen hroken up into fragments..
分裂成碎片..
By narrow domestic walls..
说真话..
Where words come out from the depth of truth..
不知疲倦追求完美..
Where tireless striving stretches its arms towards perfection..
理智没有迷失在
Where the clear stream of reason has not lost its way..
充斥死亡沉闷的沙漠里
Into the dreary desert sand of dead hahit..
你自己主导自己
Where the mind is led forward hy thee..
每一个开阔的思想和行动
Into every-widening thought and action..
进入到一个自由的天堂 神父
Into that heaven of freedom, my Father,
让我的国家觉醒吧
let my country awake..
谢谢
Thank you.